# ARAF AL-JAMI

arafaljami1331@gmail.com ⋄ araf.aljami.me ⋄ +8801755045141 ⋄ Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### **SUMMARY**

Around 2 years of working experience as a software engineer, with a strong pursuit of problem-solving. Handson experience in building enterprise applications and maintaining best practices with OOD. Followed SOLID principles and design patterns to write clean, maintainable, and adaptive code.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: C#, Typescript, Javascript, C/C++, Java, Python

Specialties: .NET, .NET Core, Node js, Express, Web API, Git, IdentityServer4, Agile, Angular

Database and messaging: MongoDB, EF Core, MySQL, MassTransit, RabbitMQ, Mqtt, Azure Service

Bus.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Shohoj Limited, Dhaka

February 2020 - Present

Software Engineer, Backend

- · Developed RESTful and gRPC APIs in event-driven microservice architecture using ASP .NET Core.
- · Developed a service to provide, **Identity Access Management** service for **3+ million users**.
- · Developed tools to migrate **3+ million users**, from **12** different user store to **1** single consolidated user store.
- · Implemented a service, to aggregate location history data in a friendly format for the data science team.
- · Worked on Shohoz Review Service, a tenant aware review rating service at scale.
- · Used TDD to write robust, adaptable code.

## SELISE rockin' software, Dhaka

November 2018 - January 2020

Software Engineer

- · Used Angular, Angular S to develop Single Page Applications
- · Used Dotnet Core technologies to develop REST API.
- · Worked on multiple projects and implemented business requirements for Selise Auditing and Certification Platform.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Leading University, Sylhet

September 2014 - April 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

## **AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

# Onsite Competitive Programming Contests

 $September\ 2014$  - Present

- $\cdot$  10<sup>th</sup> place (4<sup>th</sup> place University wise) out of **150** teams, at IUBAT ACM NCPC 2018. [link]
- · 16<sup>th</sup> place (8<sup>th</sup> place University wise) out of **120** teams, at MIST IUPC 2019

# Online Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · Active participant in online coding challenges on sites such as **TopCoder**, **Codeforces**.
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1982 (top 4%) in Codeforces. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1469 (Division 1) in TopCoder. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Solved around 2800 problems in various online judges. [link]